# Guven Gergerli

Driven by a foundation in AI, machine learning, and natural language processing, I aim to further explore the complexities of uncertainty in LLMs and develop explainable AI systems. My long-term goal is to contribute to innovative research and practical applications that enhance human-AI collaboration and advance scientific knowledge in both academic and industrial environments.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Purdue University** 

August 2023 - Present

PhD Student in Computer Science

West Lafayette, IN

• Advisor: Joseph Campbell Bilkent University

Sep 2018 - June 2023

BS in Computer Science

Ankara, Turkey

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### CAMP Lab at Purdue University

July 2024 - Present

Research Assistant

West Lafayette, IN • Developing an uncertainty-based Theory of Mind agent model to capture causal effects in a white-box design for

- long-horizon learning and reasoning. • Developing a method to infer coactivated and sparse agent intentions using offline reinforcement learning and a
- decomposed reward function for behavior prediction. **Qatar Computing Research Institute**

May 2024 - July 2024

Visiting Researcher

Doha, Qatar

- Conducted a comprehensive literature review on protein crystallization, augmenting datasets with synthetic data and evaluating models like SHARC and YOLO-V9 for improved detection accuracy.
- Developed a web application for protein crystallization detection, deployed models on platforms like Hugging Face Spaces, and optimized performance through data augmentation and hyperparameter tuning.

## Human Agent Interactions Lab at Purdue University

Aug 2023 - May 2024

Research Assistant

West Lafayette, IN

- Developed and tested robot interfaces to utilize physical robots named Furhat and NAO as a novel automated medical speech therapy for elders suffering from stroke-induced aphasia.
- Co-authored a research paper and conducted experiments using half-automated Wizard of Oz methods.

#### Turkish Airlines Technology

Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

Machine Learning Intern

Istanbul, Turkey

- Developed an ANN model to estimate annual income using a Turkish Airlines flights and revenues dataset.
- Visualized the estimated annual income on a regression graph to represent monthly and daily predicted income.

## Vela Partners

July 2022 - Aug 2022

Machine Learning Intern

San Francisco, CA

• Developed a BERT-based model to measure semantic similarity in a 650,000-company dataset and researched optimal BERT models for efficient categorization.

#### ESEN Integration System

June 2021 - Aug 2021

Software Engineer Intern

Ankara, Turkey

Istanbul, Turkey

- Developed a Python program to filter and optimize black box transmission messages for defense industry aircraft.
- Produced an HTML-based UI for data visualization of filtered transmission messages designed for mechanical engineers.

#### AirCar Corp.

July 2020 - Aug 2020

Machine Learning Intern

- Tested various object detection algorithms for top-view terrain analysis in emergency landing scenarios.
- Generated an RGB terrain dataset using drone technology for fine-tuning object detection algorithms.

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: Turkish (Native), English (Professional)
- Programming Languages: Python, Java, C, C#, C++, JavaScript, MatLab, PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Tools & Frameworks: Pytorch, Keras, Git, GitHub, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Firebase, MariaDB, Firebase, JQuery, Linux, Android Studio, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Docker
- Software Engineering Skills: Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Artificial Intelligence, Reinforcement Learning, LLM Foundation Models, LLM Fine Tuning, Data science, Object-Oriented Programming, Agile Development & Scrum, Data Structures, Requirements Engineering, Algorithm Design